[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa automation tutorial as
you all know I've already published 69
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from few videos onwards I have
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating the test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos this is our lesson 70 in terms of
overall tricentis Tsar training and this
is obstacle 28 in terms of real time
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an obstacle
where you need to scan an XML and you
need to retrieve the specific values
from the XML with the help of
constraint and we have to enter those
retrieved values into an application web
application under edit box
so now let us go to obstacle and see in
detail what is the obstacle that we need
to solve
for so this is the obstacle list that we
are working on so here is our obstacle
that we are going to start working on
the name of obstacle is get s number and
which is categorized as
hard let us go for it and understand
what is the obstacle
first you need to download the XML file
manually I don't want to automate this
one and extract the complete number
including prefix of s with
TSA so as soon as you click on catalog
it downloads you the XML file so I have
already downloaded the XML file okay let
us go to XML file so this is the XML
file let me open this XML
file you can see the XML file Here If
You observe closely this catalog has a
number with ID mic and then that ID mic
has prefix number gener in the same way
the second ID is Sue it has prefix
number and general what we need to do we
have to retrieve or we have to capture
the prefix and number of
Sue we have to capture the prefix and
number of ID Sue so let me copy this
0061 and go to
application and enter the prefix here
but again you have to also concatenate
the number of the Sue copy and paste
here so now you can see you solve the
automation problem successfully let me
try again what if instead of taking
prefix and number of so if I take prefix
prefix and number of the first one Nike
what happens we'll see okay copy this
first one
prefix and this is my
number see now your automation problem
is not solved because you're not
entering the prefix and number of ID Sue
okay so now let us go to trient tasa and
see how can we solve the
problem as usual we are going to work on
right side which is module
okay I would like to scan the object
so before scanning the objects I would
like to create a folder here so let me
create a subfolder right click and
create a sub folder module folder create
folder name this
as the obstacle name copy
this and name with obstacle name so what
we are going to do under this fer we
have
to
store both separate objects what are
those first one is we have to scan the
catalog XML which is this one I'm going
to store I'm going to store that as one
module and
also we have to scan the application
objects right I would like to store that
as separate module first let us first
scan the catalog XML what we need to do
right click on this folder go to scan go
to more and here you can find file scan
select this
one and now you need to scan the catalog
XML right so I would like to go to the
location where I have stored so this is
the location catalog I have stored right
select the catalog XML click on
open so you can see here
now there is a catalog request module
that has been created which
contains the entire Json structure it
has a catalog number ID prefix number
and general if you go to XML file
so you can see it has a
number so this is the
number number is under catalog under
catalog right under number again you
have prefix number gener see prefix
number Jer so this also has ID see under
number it has ID prefix number Jer so
that's what it is showing it is showing
the entire Json structure now let me
scan the application as well so let's
right click on this click on scan select
application now what is the application
I would like to scan this is the
application that I would like to scan on
scan
what I need I
need only this edit box number edit box
so I'm going
to take this number edit box check check
the you have to check this number edit
box and
then rename this module with the
obstacle name we already copied that one
okay let's rename this module with
obstacle
name now save the
module so once you save the module close
the X scan so let us go back to tr
testos now you can see here this is your
application related objects and this is
your XML related module now we have all
the objects that are required to
automate the test
case now let us automate the test case
for that let's go to Left module related
to test case which is blue color module
okay under obstacle folder let's create
a new test case name this with the
obstacle name double click on this now
now you need to drag and drop modules
onto the test case first I would like to
drag and drop the catalon
request onto the test case and then I
would like to drag and drop the
application related module onto the test
case so let me expand
this so here first I need to capture the
specific values from the XML to capture
the specific value from the XML first I
need to open the
XML so I need another step here to open
XML go to right click and then search
ADD test step
now here you can use
create open create XML file select this
one now this step should be at the
top so here let me name this as
catalog okay I will like to name this as
catalog Resource as catalog I'm going to
use this resource in the next steps and
what is the path file path let's go to
the file
path so this is where we stored the file
and paste it here and this is your
catalog let me name let me take the name
of XML as well
copy do
XML so that is done now come to catalog
request that we scan the XML file right
so here I would like to use the same
name here as well the resource name same
resource name and now
here under
ID we would like
to so we need to take value of prefix
and number related to the ID soe right
let's copy this
copy this
value and now I would like to use the
constraint so here I'm going to enter
Sue and I'm going to specify it as a
constraint that means I'm instructing
TSA to look for the
ID su
su then only start performing other
actions so here what I would like to do
I'm going to say prefix I'm going to
store the
value once it identifies the Sue ID then
the prefix should be stored under a
buffer name called prefix so here your
action mode should be
buffer and number I'm going to say
num also should be stored under
buffer and and now you can simply call
these two buffers to this edit box so we
need to enter the value here right so to
call the for open curly braces capital B
open Square
braces Rix close Square
braces and then close curly braces and
then you need to
concatenates and then you need to
concatenate it again I'm going to call
the other buffer open curly braces
capital B open Square braces
num Clos Square Braes close curly
Braes so you can see here now so what we
did first we are opening the
XML
catalog and then we are using constraint
method to filter out the required I ID
the required ID is Sue that's why I'm
instructing tasar to take this one once
it finds this
Sue then start buffering the values of
pref prefix and
num so before the test so this is how we
built the test case and then I'm
entering the values of buffer in the
edit box so before we create the test
case what we did for the modules first
we scan the XML that we have stored
under a local folder and then we have
scanned the application that is required
to
automate right now let us change the
work state as
completed save the test
case now let us run the test case right
click and run in scratchbook before I
done I would like to make
sure try again now let's go back here
now right click and run in
scratchbook see it entered the value
correctly so this is the prefix and this
is the number so it is able to retrieve
the values from XML and enter into the
edit box as required for the S
ID so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries hope you all
understand how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to scan an
XML and you need to retrieve the
specific values from the XML and enter
those values into an application edit
box please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you don't forget to like
and share the video
[Music]